（春夏）うーん！　うーん！　あぁ…。
（春夏）ねえ　集！
これ　開けてぇ。
Hey, Shu! Open this for me!
あれ？　どこか出掛けるのー？
Huh? Are you going out somewhere?
（集）前に言ったでしょ。
部活の合宿。
We've been over this! My club's going on a retreat.
（春夏）あー　うん。
そんなこと言ってたような…。→
Oh, yeah, I sort of feel like
you told me that... Did you?
言ってた？
言ってたの。
Yes, I did.
I'm not going to be home for a while, got it?
しばらく　うちを空けるからね。
えー！　独りぼっちで　お留守番？
What, you're leaving me to stay here all alone?!
しょうがないでしょ…。
It's not my fault, you know.
（春夏）さみしい！
私も　ついていくぅ！
I'll be lonely! I'm coming with you!
こら！　重いって。
Stop it, you're heavy!
あっ！　いのりちゃーん！
Inori! Shu says he's abandoning me!
（春夏）集が　私のこと捨てるって。
もう　いいから　離れてよ！
Enough, okay? Let go!
You're going to Oshima, right?
行き先は大島だったっけ？
うん。
Mm-hmm.
そう。
I see.
じゃあ
お父さんに会ってらっしゃい。
Pay a visit to your father, then.
♪♪～
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
I'm yours
Say, there's lots of happiness
in this world, isn't there?
Someday, if we're together
Even if someone calls you a liar
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
Even if the world tries to make
you wear a crown of thorns
Without even trying to believe in you
I can take your side, and yours alone
I know that solitude, that pain
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
（颯太）着いた　着いたー！
hot summer day
We're here, we're here!
What a nice day! I'm so glad it's not raining.
（祭）いいお天気！
晴れてよかったね！
（颯太）これから行くとこ
集の親戚の別荘なんだって？
So, I hear we're heading to
your family's vacation house now?!
U-Uh, yeah. I lived here when I was a little kid.
あ…　うん。　子供のころ
こっちに住んでたから。
いやー　助かったぜ！
Man, you sure helped us out!
アハハハ…。
Souta Tamadate?
《魂館　颯太？
それって　僕のクラスの？》
You mean the one in my class?
（涯）《そうだ。
大島まで連れてこい》
Yes. Bring him to Oshima.
We're going to infiltrate a GHQ facility there.
《そこにある
ＧＨＱの施設に潜入する》
《セキュリティーを突破するのに
そいつのヴォイドの力がいる》
We need his Void's power to
break through their security.
Of all people...
《よりによって…》
All you have to do is invite him on a trip.
You can't tell me that's hard.
《旅行に誘うだけのことだ。
難しくはあるまい》
《できるよ》
《結構》
I can do it.
Very good. Always cherish your friends.
《友達は大切にしろ》
《涯のやつ
人の気も知らずに…》
Stupid Gai. He has no clue how I feel.
Whoa! This place is so posh!
おー　すげえ！　立派だな。
What do your relatives do for a living, Ouma?
（花音）桜満君の親戚って
何をしている人なの？
えっ…。
Er...
どうしたの？　このお屋敷。
What's with this mansion?
（いのり）供奉院グループが
手配したって　涯が。
Gai said the Kuhouin Group arranged it for us.
There you two go getting affectionate again.
また　２人　仲良くして。
家だけにしてよー。
Save it for when you're at home, okay?
Wh-Where did that come from?
な…　何　言ってんの？　いきなり。
だって
２人　一緒に住んでるんでしょ？
You do live together, don't you?
Huh? What do you mean?
（花音）何？　どういうこと？
（颯太）俺　見ちゃったんだよね。→
I caught 'em in the act!
I saw them going home together.
２人が一緒に　家に帰ってくの。→
Let's ask them. How did your romance begin?
ちょっと聞いてみましょう！
２人の　なれ初めは？
Come on, stop it!
There's nothing between Inori and me.
やめてよ！
いのりとは何もないよ。
She's got a violent older brother,
and I happen to know him, so...
乱暴な　お兄さんがいて
その人が　僕の知り合いで…。
Yeah, yeah. We don't need to hear excuses!
はいはい。
言い訳は　いいでーす。
幸せな人は　ほっといて
もう　今から　海行こうぜ　海！
Let's leave the happy couple alone
and go hit the beach! Beach time!
Wait, shouldn't we unpack and...
ちょっとは片付けとか…。
（颯太）そんなの　後　後！
That can wait!
せっかくのリゾートだぜ！
今は　目いっぱい遊ばなきゃ！
We're at a resort, guys!
We gotta have all the fun we can!
Tamadate!
魂館君！
We're at the beach! Woo-hoo!
（颯太）海だー！　ヤッホー！
Hurry up, everybody!
≪（颯太）みんな　早く来いよー！
（花音）まったく。　強引なんだから。
Jeez, he's so pushy!
（祭）アハハ。
颯太君らしいよ。
He's just being himself.
やれやれ…。
Sheesh...
《僕は　颯太が苦手だ》
I have a hard time dealing with Souta.
《強引で　デリカシーがなくて
空気読まなくて》
He's pushy, and he's got no delicacy,
and he doesn't read social cues...
If it weren't for the mission,
I'd never go on a trip with him...
《ミッションがなければ
一緒に旅行なんて…》
《旅行…　なんて…》
A trip...
油断してたんだよね　私…。
頑張れ　祭！
I let my guard down, didn't I?
Give it your best, Hare!
（祭）ねえ　集！
Hey, Shu!
Let's go swim with them!
私たちも泳ごうよ。
Uh... um...
あ…　えっと…。
ほら！　早く！
Hurry up!
Hey...
ちょっ…！　祭！？
Hare!
ちょっと待ってって！
Hey, wait!
♪♪～
"Spirits of the Dead"
（四分儀）魂館　颯太は
無事　たどりついたようですね。
It seems Souta Tamadate
made it here without issue.
（アルゴ）ミッションだってのに
浮かれやがって。
He's having way too much
fun for someone on a mission!
Should we really be lettin' them goof off?
あんなん　やらせてていいのか？
（大雲）ここまでは順調です。
Everything is going well so far.
The issue here is the facility's security.
問題は
施設のセキュリティーでしょう。
（四分儀）そちらは
鶫たちが調査中です。
Tsugumi and Ayase are looking into that now.
So we're just on standby for a while, huh?
（アルゴ）しばらくは待機か。→
しかし　こんな島に
いったい何があるってんだ？
What the hell is there on
this island anyway, though?
"Gai only knows," as it were.
（四分儀）それは
涯のみぞ知るです。→
Say, Argo...
ところで　アルゴ。
あん？
Aren't you overheated?
（四分儀）暑くないのですか？
（アルゴ）気合　入ってますんで。
Well, I'm fired up.
あれ？　集は？
Huh? Where's Shu?
He left before us.
He said he had a stop to make.
寄る所があるって
先に行ったけど？
Come to think of it,
Oshima is where his father's...
そういえば　大島って
集のお父さんの…。
あっ？
あのー　これ！
Um, I caught this!
Thank you.
（綾瀬）ありがとう。→
Good afternoon.
ご機嫌よう。
（颯太）すっげー！
お嬢さまって感じだな。
Whoa! She had a real "classy rich girl" vibe!
Tsugumi, why are you in that ridiculous getup?
（綾瀬）鶫！
何　そのふざけた格好。
Your outfit looks wonderful
on you too, Miss Ayase.
（鶫）綾瀬お嬢さまも
とってもお似合いですわよ。
オホホホ！
≪（足音）
桜満クロス博士か。
知ってるの？
Dr. Kurosu Ouma, eh?
You know about him?
He was a professor at the old Tennozu University.
旧天王洲大学の教授だ。
And the leading expert on the Apocalypse Virus.
アポカリプスウイルス研究の
第一人者でもある。
そうだったんだ。
なぜ　お前が知らない？
Oh, wow.
Why don't you know about him?
家では　そういう話　しないから。
We don't talk about stuff like that at home.
春夏の先生だったとは
聞いてるけど。
I did know he was Haruka's teacher...
春夏？
いや　うちの母親だけど…。
"Haruka"?
Oh, she's my mom.
とにかく　父さんのことは
あまり覚えてないんだ。
Anyway, I don't really remember my dad.
１０年前に死んじゃったから。
ロストクリスマスか。
He died ten years ago, after all.
Lost Christmas, eh?
Everything changed after that day.
あの日から
何もかもが変わってしまった…。
ところで
どうして　ここに来たの？
Say, what are you doing here?
お墓参りじゃないよね。
ああ。
It's not to visit a grave, is it?
No.
あれだ。
That.
A shrine?
神社？
こいつで見てみろ。
Look at it with these.
あれって…！
Is that...
It's a secret GHQ facility. What I want is inside.
ＧＨＱの秘密施設だ。
あそこに求めるものがある。
「求めるもの」？
What you want?
はじまりの石。
The rock that started it all.
That's what we need to get
our hands on most right now.
今　俺たちが　最も
手に入れなくてはならないものだ。
You and the Void you draw
are the key to that operation.
その作戦の鍵が
お前と　お前の出すヴォイド。
I trust you understand.
分かってるな？
Souta Tamadate... Yeah, I understand.
魂館　颯太。
分かってるよ。
ミッションの開始は　２２００。
The mission begins at 2200.
それまでに　あいつを
指定のポイントまで連れてこい。
Bring him to the designated point by then.
簡単に言うよなぁ…。
実際　簡単だろう。
You make it sound so easy...
It is easy. Just use bait.
餌を使えばいい。
餌？
Bait?
ＥＧＯＩＳＴのファンだと
聞いているが？
I hear he's an Egoist fan.
いのりを使うの！？
そんなん　嫌だよ！
Use Inori?! I don't like that!
Why not?
なぜ嫌がる？　相手の
興味のあるものを使って引っ張る。
You use something the other person
is interested in to bring him in.
初歩の初歩だ。
それが　いのりでも！？
It's the most basic play there is.
Even if the "something" is Inori?!
I can see there's no point in arguing any further.
これ以上の議論は無意味だな。
できないなら　やらなくていい。
お前は寝ていろ。
If you can't do it, you don't
have to. Just stay in bed.
Hey!
ちょっと…。　待ってよ！
Wait!
I haven't gone on a trip with friends in forever!
（祭）友達と旅行なんて久しぶり。
花音ちゃんも
来てくれて　ありがとうね。
Thanks for coming with us, Kanon.
何　言ってるの。
私だって　一応　映研部員よ。
What are you talking about?
I am a member of the club, you know.
幽霊部員だけど…。
Even if in name only.
（祭）でも　谷尋君　来てないのに…。
But since Yahiro didn't come...
今は　あいつ　関係ないでしょ！
He doesn't have anything to do with this!
本当に助かったよ～。
I'm so glad you're here.
If I were all alone with Yuzuriha, I'd...
（祭）《もし　楪さんと
２人きりだったら　私…》
≪（戸の開閉音）
（花音）あっ！
いのりちゃん　肌　奇麗！→
Wow, Inori, you've got great skin!
ねえねえ　触ってもいい？
えっ？　あの…。
Hey, can I touch you?!
Huh? Um...
Whoa! It's so smooth!
すごーい！　すべすべ～！
じゃあ　ここは？
What about here, then?
あ…。　そこ　駄目…。
Don't... touch there...
I wonder how Yuzuriha feels about Shu.
（祭）《楪さんは　集のこと
どう思ってるんだろ？》
（颯太）なあ　集。
Hey, Shu.
えっ。　何？
What?
（颯太）いのりちゃんとは
ホントに何もないわけ？
Is there really nothing between you and Inori?
I told you before, there really isn't...
さっきも言ったじゃない。
ホントに何でも…。
If there isn't, I'm going for it.
何でもないなら　俺　いくから。
はっ？
いのりちゃん。　俺　いくから。
I'm going for it with Inori.
♪♪～
今晩　いく？
Want to start tonight?
♪♪～
A mission you drag your friends into...
（四分儀）「友人を巻き込むミッション桜満君には不向きの任務ですね」
It's certainly not a job that suits Ouma.
俺の意見は違うな。
巻き込んでこその友さ。
I disagree. That's what friends are for.
（四分儀）「フフッ。　あなたらしい」
That sounds like you.
A life with no adventure in it is boring.
何の冒険もない人生なんて
つまらん。
ちょっとくらいは　人の心に
波風立てるくらいでないとな。
The least a friend can do is
stir up a little trouble in your heart.
（亞里沙）恙神　涯…。
Gai Tsutsugami.
（ウエーター）お客さま。
（ダリル）何だよ！？
Sir.
What do you want?
えっ！
Are you sure about this?
（秘書）よろしいのですか？
（ヤン）構わん。→
It doesn't matter. I'm not entirely
convinced he's even my son.
本当に私の子なのかも
怪しいものだ。
（ヤン）あれの母親は
よくない女だった。
His mother was a no-good woman.
Unlike you.
君と違ってな。
（颯太）ごめんね　急にさ。
Sorry this was so sudden.
星が奇麗だよね。
東京じゃ　めったに…。
The stars are really pretty, huh?
We hardly ever see them in Tokyo... well,
I guess this is Tokyo too, huh.
って　ここも東京か。
（颯太）ハハ…　ハハハ…。
《問題ない》
It's not a problem. There's no problem
with leaving them alone together.
《２人きりにしても
何も問題ない》
見せたいものがあるんだ。
There's something I want to show you.
俺　ＥＧＯＩＳＴのＰＶで
すごく感動して→
I was so touched by Egoist's promo
video, I just couldn't contain myself.
居ても立ってもいられなくて…。
だから　自分でも作ってみたんだ。
So I tried making one of my own.
あっ。
《何やってんの？》
What's he doing?
Blooming wildflower
♪♪「咲いた　野の花よ」
♪♪「ああ　どうか…」
- I beg you, please tell me
《僕みたいなことして…》
- He's doing something I'd do...
- I beg you, please tell me
《誰でも　それで
いのりの気を引けるとでも…》
- Does he think Inori'll be interested
- I beg you, please tell me
- in just any guy who does that?
奇麗。
あっ！
- It's pretty.
- Why do people fight and hurt each other?
- I-Inori!
（颯太）い…　いのりちゃん！
- I... I don't know you very well yet, but...
- Why do people fight and hurt each other?
俺　いのりちゃんのこと
まだ　よく知らないけどさ→
- When your singing moved me, that feeling was real!
- Why do people fight and hurt each other?
歌う君に感動した気持ちは
本当なんだ！
いのりちゃんのこと
もっと知りたい！
I want to know you better, Inori!
俺　いのりちゃんのこと→
Because I... really... li-li...
本気で　すっ…！
（颯太）す…！
ちょっと待って！！
Hold it right there!
（颯太）集！？
Shu?!
お前　何で…？
Why are you here?!
いのりは　僕の…！
Inori is my...
（颯太）うおっ！
（颯太）うあぁぁぁ！！
集。
Shu.
あっ…。
Hey, what's the big idea?
Don't draw that thing out here!
（アルゴ）おい　何やってんだ！
こんなとこで
引き抜いてんじゃねえよ。
うわああ！
いつから　そこに！？
How long have you been there?!
うっ！
こらえ性のない男ね。
You have no self-control.
綾瀬！
Ayase?
"Inori is my...!"
（鶫）「いのりは　僕の…！」
ちょ　ちょっと…！
想定外の事態です。
H-Hey!
This is an unexpected development.
What now, Gai?
どうしますか？　涯。
えー！？
プランの変更は　なしだ。
このままでいく。　いいな。
There'll be no change of plans.
We'll go now, as is. Got it?
（鶫）アイアーイ！
Aye-aye!
"Inori is my" what?
「いのりは　僕の」　何？
全員　揃ったか。
We're all here, then?
警備の目は　鶫がつぶしている。
ハァ…　ハァ…。
Tsugumi's blinded the guards.
The issue is what's inside here.
問題なのは内部だ。
大曇。
Oogumo!
（大曇）イエス。
ハァ…。
Yes, Sir.
告白は　きちんとするべきです。
When you confess your feelings,
you should do a proper job.
うん？
集。　そのカメラでゲートを撮れ。
Shu, shoot the gate with that camera.
Is this a Void for opening things?
もしかして　これって
開くヴォイド？
Let's go.
行くぞ。
うん？→
何だ！
What's your business?
あっ　失礼しました！　茎道…。
（茎道）気にしなくていい。
My apologies, Chief Keido...
Don't worry about it.
（茎道）通りすがりの生き霊だ。
I'm just a wraith passing by.
≪（アラーム）
まさか　バレたの！？
Could they be on to us?
No, this isn't about us. This is...
違う。　俺たちじゃない。
これは…。
急げ！
Hurry!
Shu!
集！
Let's go.
行くぞ。
♪♪～
Why would a Void like this come from inside Souta?
どうして　颯太の中から
こんなヴォイドが…。
I couldn't care less about the reason.
俺には　理由など　どうでもいい。
重要なのは→
The important thing...
このような仕掛けでも→
...is that his Void can "open"
even a mechanism like this.
そのヴォイドならば
開くということだ。
何なの？　この部屋。
What is this room?
この先に目的のものがある。
撮れ。
Our objective lies ahead. Shoot.
♪♪～
あっ…。
これって！？
あっ！
Does this mean?!
≪（銃声）
涯！　何を…。
Gai? What are you?
撤収する。
We're withdrawing.
くっ！
やはり　貴様か。　茎道！
I might have known it was you, Keido.
（茎道）幸福な日々を思うより
なお　大いなる苦しみは　なし。→
"The double grief of a lost bliss
is to recall its happy hour in pain"...
クロス。→
Kurosu.
I won't stop.
私は止まらんよ。
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
（颯太）集。→
Shu...
Huh? Where's Inori?!
あれ？　いのりちゃんは？
She went back.
帰ったよ。
What's your problem?
何だよ？
颯太。
僕　協力するの　やめるよ。
Souta.
I'm not going to help you anymore.
あっ！
お前
やっぱり　いのりちゃんのこと…。
You have feelings for Inori after all, don't you?
そういうふうに思ってんなら
最初から　正直に言ってくれよ！
If you feel that way,
then be honest about it up front!
何考えてんだか
さっぱり分かんねえよ！
I can't even imagine what you're thinking!
颯太だって！
You're no better!
いつも強引で　デリカシーなくて
空気読まなくて！
You're always pushy and you've got
no delicacy and you don't read social cues!
そういうところが嫌なんだよ！
あっ…。
That really bothers me about you!
I have a hard time dealing with you, Souta.
僕は　颯太のことが苦手だ。
He must hate me now.
But this was the right thing.
《嫌われたな。　でも　これでいい》
《本気で　ぶつからなくちゃ
いけなかったんだ》
I should've confronted him honestly before.
《友達なんだとしたら》
If he was my friend, anyway...
（颯太）そうじゃないかと思った。
あっ！
I thought you might.
颯太？
はっきり言ってもらって　よかった。
Souta?
I'm glad you gave it to me straight.
I mean, you're kind of distant, you know?
集ってさ
何か　距離ある感じするじゃん？
So...
だから→
ホントは　俺も　ちょっと
お前のこと苦手だったんだよ。
The truth is, it was a little hard
for me to deal with you, too.
だから　よかった。
正直に言ってくれて。
So I'm glad that you were honest.
それって
心を開いてくれたってことだろ？
That means you've opened up to me, right?
あっ！
♪♪～
いまさらだけど→
I know it's a little late to
wonder this, but... what are Voids?
ヴォイドって何だろう？
I haven't really gotten them so far,
but I get the feeling I have to.
今まで　よく分からなかったけど
それじゃあ　駄目な気がするんだ。
だって　この右手は
人の心に触れてるんだから。
I mean, after all, my right hand
is touching people's hearts.
Gai told me that Voids change along
with the states of people's hearts.
涯が言ってた。
「心のありようで
ヴォイドも変わっていく」って。
ヴォイドが？
Voids do?
そうなんだ。
Oh...
《じゃあ　心を通わせれば→
So does that mean if I form a bond
with someone, my power changes too?
僕の力も
変わっていくんだろうか？》
I'll never be loved by you again
♪♪～
Or needed by you again, either
And so here I am, all alone
What did you say that day?
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Hopeless wish today
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
Your hand in mine was warm and kind